<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2 on Steven Golovkine</title>
    <link>https://stevengolovkine.netlify.com/publication_types/2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2 on Steven Golovkine</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; {year} Steven Golovkine. All Rights Reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://stevengolovkine.netlify.com/publication_types/2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Learning the smoothness of noisy curves with application to online curve estimation</title>
      <link>https://stevengolovkine.netlify.com/publication/learning-smoothness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevengolovkine.netlify.com/publication/learning-smoothness/</guid>
      <description>Combining information both within and across trajectories, we propose a simple estimator for the local regularity of the trajectories of a stochastic process. Independent trajectories are measured with errors at randomly sampled time points. Non-asymptotic bounds for the concentration of the estimator are derived. Given the estimate of the local regularity, we build a nearly optimal local polynomial smoother from the curves from a new, possibly very large sample of noisy trajectories. We derive non-asymptotic pointwise risk bounds uniformly over the new set of curves. Our estimates perform well in simulations. Real data sets illustrate the effectiveness of the new approaches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clustering multivariate functional data using unsupervised binary trees</title>
      <link>https://stevengolovkine.netlify.com/publication/clustering-mfd/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevengolovkine.netlify.com/publication/clustering-mfd/</guid>
      <description>A model-based clustering algorithm is proposed for a general class of functional data for which the components could be curves or images. The random functional data realizations could be measured with errors at discrete, and possibly random, points in the definition domain. The idea is to build a set of binary trees by recursive splitting of the observations. The number of groups are determined in a data-driven way. The new algorithm provides easily interpretable results and fast predictions for online data sets. Results on simulated datasets reveal good performance in various complex settings. The methodology is applied to the analysis of vehicle trajectories on a German roundabout.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
