<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>0 on Steven Golovkine</title>
    <link>https://stevengolovkine.netlify.com/publication_types/0/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 0 on Steven Golovkine</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; {year} Steven Golovkine. All Rights Reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://stevengolovkine.netlify.com/publication_types/0/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>funestim</title>
      <link>https://stevengolovkine.netlify.com/software/funestim/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevengolovkine.netlify.com/software/funestim/</guid>
      <description>&lt;code&gt;funestim&lt;/code&gt; is an &lt;strong&gt;R&lt;/strong&gt;-package that allows users to estimate the mean and the covariance of a functional dataset using an estimation of the regularity of the curves. The curves can be irregularly sampled.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>simulater</title>
      <link>https://stevengolovkine.netlify.com/software/simulater/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevengolovkine.netlify.com/software/simulater/</guid>
      <description>&lt;code&gt;simulater&lt;/code&gt; is an &lt;strong&gt;R&lt;/strong&gt;-package that allows users to generated realistic functional dataset. The simulated data can be irregularly sampled. It is based on an estimation of the mean, covariance and noise functions of the real data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>denoisr</title>
      <link>https://stevengolovkine.netlify.com/software/denoisr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevengolovkine.netlify.com/software/denoisr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;code&gt;denoisr&lt;/code&gt; is an &lt;strong&gt;R&lt;/strong&gt;-package which permits to smooth (remove the noise from) functional data by, first, estimate the Hurst coefficient of the underlying generating process.
Functional data to smooth should be defined on a univariate compact, but can be irregularly sampled. &lt;code&gt;denoisr&lt;/code&gt; can also be used only for Hurst parameter estimation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FDApy</title>
      <link>https://stevengolovkine.netlify.com/software/fdapy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevengolovkine.netlify.com/software/fdapy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;code&gt;FDApy&lt;/code&gt; is an implementation of functional data as &lt;strong&gt;Python&lt;/strong&gt; package. This package provide modules for the analysis of such data. It includes classes for different dimensional data as well as irregularly sampled functional data. Moreover, a simulation toolbox is provided. It might be used to simulate different clusters of functional data. Some methodologies to handle these data are implemented, such as dimension reduction and clustering ones. New methods can easily be added. The package is publicly available on the Python Package Index and Github.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
